A Finding Aid to the Terrain Gallery Records, circa 1950s-2005, bulk 1955-1985, in the Archives of American Art AAA.terrgall
Archives of American Art
Terrain Gallery records
circa 1950s-2005
bulk 1955-1985
AAA.terrgall
Archives of American Art
5.3 Linear feet
The records of the Terrain Gallery measure 5.3 linear feet and date from circa 1950s-2005, bulk 1955-1985. The bulk of the records consists of of exhibition files that document over one hundred and forty exhibitions as well as the gallery's relationship with artists. The collection includes founding documents, correspondence, artists' files, writings and an interview, financial records, scrapbooks, and photographs.
Terrain Gallery
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Terrain Gallery records were donated by Chaim and Dorothy Koppelman in 2006.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Historical Note
In 1955, the Terrain Gallery opened under the direction of artist Dorothy Koppelman at 20 West 16th Street in New York City. In 1973, the Terrain Gallery relocated to its present location at 141 Greene Street in SoHo to share space with the Aesthetic Realism Foundation.
In 1954, Dorothy Koppelman (1920-), her husband Chaim Koppelman (1920-2009) formed a partnership with colleagues, many of them artists, writers, photographers, and others, to establish the Terrain Gallery. Influenced by the Aesthetic Realism philosophy of Eli Siegel and his Theory of Opposites, the members held that a common thread can be found in diverging styles and techniques; they maintained that unity in the arts is created by opposing elements. Accordingly, the Terrain has adopted as its motto, "in reality opposites are one; art shows this." The Terrain has featured paintings, sculptures, watercolors, and graphics; photographic exhibitions have shown the work of younger and established photographers, e.g., David Bernstein, Louis Dienes, Nat Herz, and Andre Kertesz.
Chaim Koppelman, for many years, headed the gallery's Print Division; printmakers such as Will Barnet, Leonard Baskin, Robert Conover, and Nicholas Krushenick were frequent exhibitors. Though the Terrain does not maintain a stable of artists, the gallery has represented many well-known artists, including: Richard Anuszkiewicz, Richard Artschwager, Robert Blackburn, Mark Di Suvero, Lois Dodd, Chaim and Dorothy Koppelman, Roy Lichtenstein, Claes Oldenburg, Clayton Pond, Larry Rivers, Clare Romano, and Arnold Schmidt.
Beginning in 1955 with a series of talks by the Seurat Art Club, the gallery has held lectures, seminars, and dramatic presentations that are open to artists, scholars, and the general public. As part of its educational outreach, the Terrain Gallery has a printing division, Definition Press that publishes catalogs, broadsides, announcements, and monographs relating to Aesthetic Realism.
In 1972, the Terrain Gallery appointed Carrie Wilson to serve as co-director with Dorothy Koppelman. The following year, the Terrain became part of the Aesthetic Realism Foundation. The Terrain Gallery continues to hold exhibitions and presentations dedicated to the principles of Aesthetic Realism. Chaim Koppelman died in 2009 in New York City. Dorothy Koppelman (1920-) is a consultant on the faculty of Aesthetic Realism Foundation.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the Terrain Gallery measure 5.3 linear feet and date from circa 1950s-2005, bulk 1955-1985. The bulk of the records consists of of exhibition files that document over one hundred and forty exhibitions as well as the gallery's relationship with artists. The collection includes founding documents, correspondence, artists' files, writings and an interview, financial records, scrapbooks, and photographs.
Founding documents include statements of purpose, notes outlining plans for establishing a gallery, letters, and lists of expenses. Included are several versions of the gallery's manifesto "For the Union of Aesthetics and Ethics," drafted by founding members, Martha Baird, Louis and Regina Dienes, Nat Herz, Chaim and Dorothy Koppelman, Sheldon Kranz, Barbara Lekberg, Nancy Starrels, and others.
Correspondence consists of letters between Dorothy Koppelman and artists, museums, and arts organizations. Subjects discussed are the scheduling of exhibitions and the gallery's lending of artwork to cultural institutions. Included are Dorothy's letters to art critics, e.g., Dore Ashton, Thomas Hess, and Hilton Kramer seeking press coverage for the gallery's exhibitions. Among the frequent correspondents are Sigmund Abeles, American Federation of Arts, Philip Bragar, Lawrence Campbell, Museum of Modern Art (New York), Peter Milton, Lee Nordness, Andrew Rush, and Lyn Ward. Also found are scattered letters from Chaim Koppelman, Eli Siegel, and Theodoros Stamos.
Artists' files document approximately seventy artists and include curriculum vitae, letters, and scattered materials, e.g., exhibition brochures and invitations. Exhibition files provide an overview of the gallery's dealings with artists, museums, and the press, with the bulk of the material dating from 1955-1985. Materials include biographical information, correspondence, sales of artwork, printed material, photographs of exhibition installations and artwork.
Writings and an interview contain annotated typescripts and handwritten drafts on Aesthetic Realism by Chaim and Dorothy Koppelman and others. Included are several draft versions of David Bourdon's interview with Chaim and Dorothy Koppelman. The Koppelmans' discuss the influence of Aesthetic Realism in their personal and professional lives as well as the critical response by the press and others to Aesthetic Realism's place in art history.
Financial and legal records consist of ledgers, financial reports, sales and loans, and consignment receipts, with the majority of the records dating from 1955-1983; scattered legal materials document the incorporation of the Terrain Gallery with the Aesthetic Realism Foundation. Five scrapbooks contain a variety of exhibition materials: letters, statements about the gallery, lists, announcements, and printed material. Two scrapbooks chronicle the gallery's early exhibitions from 1955 through 1960. The other scrapbooks document three exhibitions held at the Terrain Gallery.
Photographs are of Chaim and Dorothy Koppelman, Harold Jacobs, Gerson Leiber, Vincent Longo, Ad Reinhardt, and others. There are a few photographs of artwork by Michael Ponce de Leon and Edith Schloss.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 8 series:
Series 1: Founding Documents, 1953-1966 (Box 1; 0.1 linear feet)
Series 2: Correspondence, circa 1950s-1981 (Box 1; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 3: Artists' Files, circa 1950s-2001 (Box 1; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 4: Exhibition Files, circa 1950s-2005 (Boxes 1-4, 6; 3.2 linear feet)
Series 5: Writings and Interview, 1955-1974 (Boxes 4-5; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 6: Financial and Legal Records, 1955-1984 (Box 5; 0.8 linear feet)
Series 7: Scrapbooks, 1955-2000 (Boxes 5, 6; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 8: Photographs, 1957-circa 1980s (Box 5; 0.1 linear feet)
Related Archival Materials note
Also found in the Archives of American Art is the Chaim and Dorothy Koppelman papers, circa 1930s-2006, bulk 1942-2005.
Abeles, Sigmund, 1934-; American Federation of Arts; Ashton, Dore; Bourdon, David; Bragar, Philip F., 1925-; Campbell, Lawrence; Hess, Thomas B.; Jacobs, Harold, 1932-; Koppelman, Chaim, 1920---Photographs; Koppelman, Chaim, 1920-; Koppelman, Dorothy--Photographs; Koppelman, Dorothy; Kramer, Hilton; Leiber, Gerson August, 1921-; Longo, Vincent, 1923-; Milton, Peter, 1930-; Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.); Nordness, Lee; Reinhardt, Ad, 1913-1967--Photographs; Rush, Andrew; Siegel, Eli, 1902-; Stamos, Theodoros, 1922-1997; Ward, Lynd, 1905-; Wilson, Carrie; Aesthetic Realism; Art galleries, Commercial--New York (State)--New York; Art-Philosophy; Interviews; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Transcripts
- Founding Documents, 1953-1966; Series 1; 0.1 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Founding documents include letters, typescripts and handwritten plans for the gallery, progress reports, mailing lists, projected expenses and notes. Included is Dorothy Koppelman's annotated typescript "Some Notions with a Hope of Motion on a Gallery," which served as a basis for the Terrain's mission statement.
  Founding documents are also located in Series 5: Financial Records.
  - Plans for Establishment of the Terrain Gallery, 1953-1956; 1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters to Investors in the Terrain Gallery, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Report on the Terrain Gallery's Tenth Anniversary, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, circa 1950s-1981; Series 2; 0.2 Linear feet Box 1
  This series consists of typescripts, handwritten letters, notes, telegrams, and postcards. Many of the letters have attachments, e.g., biographical information, receipts, invoices, checklists, consignment agreements, loan forms, printed material, exhibition announcements, and brochures. A file concerning the gallery's lending of work to museum and other art organizations includes correspondence, notes, delivery receipts, invoices, price lists, and other business-related information.
  Additional correspondence can be found in Series 3: Exhibition Files and Series 6: Scrapbooks.
  Arrangement note
  Files are arranged in chronological order.
  - Correspondence, circa 1950s-1981; undated (Box 1, Folder 4-13)
- Artists' Files, circa 1950s-2001; Series 3; 0.2 Linear feet Box 1
  Artists' files mostly contain curriculum vitae and biographical accounts of artists, some who were not represented by the gallery. Also found are exhibition brochures, invitations, letters; miscellaneous artists' files include a letter to Dorothy Koppelman, typescripts of comments by artists on their work, writings, and a list.
  - A-B, circa 1960-1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Abeles, Sigmund
    Allman, Margot
    Almarez, Carlos D.
    Altman, Harold
    Baranoff, Mort
    Bayrak, Tosun
    Blaustein, Al
    Boyer, Francis
    Bragar, Philip F.
    Brown Hilton
  - C-D, circa 1950s-1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Cady, Dennis
    Cassara, Frank
    Chusit, Sonia
    Citron, Minna
    Clutz, William
    Collins, Lloyd D.
    Condeso, Orlando
    Conover, Robert
    Cooper, Michael
    Cullum, Adrienne
    Day, Worden
    DeMauro, Don
    Dicosola, Lois
  - E-F, undated; 1957 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Erlanger, Elisabeth
    Farrar, Joan
  - G-H, 1954-circa 1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Garchik, Morton
    Gelb, Jan
    Gerardia, Helen
    Gillies, Jim
    Gonzalez-Tornero, Sergio
    Goudie, Harland
    Gray, Don
    Grotz, Dorothy
    Hahn, Gerald
    Haley, Priscilla J.
    Hamill, Timothy J.
    Hildenbrand, June
  - J-L, circa 1955-2001 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Janko, May
    Kaplan, Jerome
    Kepets, Hugh
    Koppelman, Chaim
    Leaf, Ruth
    Leff, Juliette
    Leiber, Gerson
    Levine, Morris
    Longo, Vincent
    Lozowick, Louis
  - M-N, circa 1955-1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Marano, Alberto
    Margo, Boris
    Margules, DeHirsh
    Marmelstein, Michael
    Milton, Peter
    Mommer, Paul
    Moy, Seong
    Nama, George
    Neustadt, Barbara
  - O-P, circa 1960-1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Otreba, Ryszard K.
    Parker, Robert Andrew
    Peterdi, Gabor
    Pinkwater, Manus
    Pittinger, Robert
    Plotkin, Robert
    Presser, Josef
  - R, 1958-circa 1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Romano, Clare
    Rosenhouse, Irwin
    Ross, John
    Rush, Andrew
  - S-T, circa 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Seidler, Doris
    Smith, Moise
    Stasik, Andrew
    Tremain, Joyce
  - U-W, circa 1954-1965 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Uchima, Toshiko
    Von Wicht, John
    Ward, Lyn
  - Miscellaneous Artists' Files, undated; 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Exhibition Files, circa 1950s-2005; Series 4; 3.2 Linear feet Boxes 1-4, 6
  This series documents the exhibition history of the Terrain Gallery beginning with its first exhibit in 1955 through 2005, with the majority of the files dating from 1955-1985. Exhibition files include curriculum vitae, artists' statements, correspondence, drafts, receipts for artwork on consignment, checklists, price lists, exhibition agreements, business-related information, and photographs of exhibition installations and images of a few artists. Among the printed materials are press releases, posters, brochures, announcements, and clippings of reviews. There are typescripts of interviews with Dorothy and Chaim Koppelman.
  Files are arranged in the order they were received. There were two filing systems for exhibition materials: general exhibitions consisting of printed material and files on individual exhibits, both arranged in chronological order.
  The remaining files are arranged by subject and thereafter in chronological order.
  - Exhibitions (Box 1)
    - Exhibitions, General, 1955-2003 (Box 1, Folder 25-54)
    - "Logic and Emotion" (1955) (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - "Intersection" (1955 April-May), 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - "Chaim Koppelman Retrospective, 1940-1955," (1956 January 23-February 29) (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - "Abstract and Concrete" (1956 March 3-March 30) (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - "Depth and Surface" (1956 April 9-May 15) (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - "Tension and Symmetry" (1956 May 21-June) (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - "Aesthetic Realists and Friends" (1956), 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - "Three Painters: William Christopher, Regina Dienes, and Gerson Leiber" (1956 December 17-1957 January), 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - "Are Black and White One? - Paintings, Drawings, Prints, and Photographs" (1957) (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - "Black and White - Festival of Opposites" (1957) (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - "Summer Festival of Opposites: Rest and Motion" (1957 May 20-June), 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - "Opposites in Contemporary Art - Aesthetic Realists and Friends" (1957) (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - "Personal and Impersonal" (1957), 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - "Design into Emotion" (1958), 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - "Person:Thing:Form" (1958) (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - "Three Persons: Three Elements: Schilli Maier, Regina Dienes, and William Christopher" (1958), 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - "Meaning in Immediacy" (1958) (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - "In the First Place" (1958 October 18-October 19) (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - "Abstraction in Self" (1959) (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - "Regina Dienes" (1959) (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - "Personal and Impersonal, Six Aesthetic Realists" (1959) (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - "Sculpture, The Shaping Mind" (1959) (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - "Odd and Even" (1959) (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - "Radiant Hidden" (1960) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "The Slim Weltanschauung; or the Spirit of Spring" (1960), 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "The Real-Show, an Exhibition of Paintings" (1960) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Regina Dienes" (1960), 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Definition is Wonder" (1961), 1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "Definition is Wonder - Travelling Shows" (1961), 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - "An Exhibition of Color Photographs by Nat Herz" (1961) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - "Dorothy Koppelman, One-Man Exhibition" (1961) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - "Art As Gaiety" (1961) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - "Vision and Division, A Show-Down Exhibition" (1962) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - "Louis Dienes, Photographs" (1962) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - "The Visual Argument, Paintings of William Sebring and James Mellon" (1962 April 23-May 25) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - "Chaim and Dorothy Koppelman, An Exhibition of Paintings and Drawings" (1962), 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - "Us Revisited, Dorothy Koppelman and Chaim Koppelman" (1963), 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - "The Quarreling Arts: A Classy Retrospective and Anticipatory Show" (1964) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - "The New York Show - 1964 (The Opposites Are Always New)," (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - "Arnold Schmidt: Optical Painting" (1964 October 5-November 6) (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - "Articulate Surface: Drawings" (1964), 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - "Arnold Schmidt: The Responsive Eye" (1964), 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - "The Visual Self" (1965 January 24-February) (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - "Above/Below, An Exhibition of Contemporary American Graphics" (1965) (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - "Richard Bernstein" (1965), 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - "James Mellon" (1965 June 6-July 3), 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - "Direction '65" (1965 August-September 7) (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - "Arnold Schmidt, New Optical Paintings" (1965 October 3- October 30), 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - "Harold Krisel Prints" (1965 November 1-November 30) (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - "Lui Shou Kwan" (1965) (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - "Surface to Begin With" (1965), 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - "Seena Donneson" (1966 January 17-February 18), 1957-1971 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - "Arnold Schmidt, Shaped Optical Paintings" (1966 October 2-October 30), 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - "Group Show" (1966 November 15-December) (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - "All Artists for Life and Against the War in Vietnam" (1967 February-March), 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - "Lou Bernstein's Photographs, A 25 Year Retrospective" (1967 November 12-December), 1965 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Arnold Schmidt Exhibitions at the Terrain Gallery and Other Venues, 1965-1972 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - "New Paintings by Arnold Schmidt" (1968 October 6-October 31), 1993 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - "Dorothy and Chaim Koppelman" (1969) (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - "James Mellon" (1970), 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - "You and I See, An Aesthetic Realism Photographers Exhibition" (1970 April 26-June), 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - "Is Beauty the Making One of Opposites? - Photographers" (1970) (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - "The Intimate and the Distant" (1972) (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - "Terrain Graphics" (1972), 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - "Big and Small, A Miniature Print Exhibition" (1972), 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - "Linda Plotkin, Landscape and Thought" (1973 January 20-February 10), 1966-1973 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - "Andrew B. Gardner, Silkscreen Prints" (1973 February 10-March 3) (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - "Chuck Magistro" (1973 March 10-March 30) (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - "Philip Field, Etchings" (1973 March 31-April 20), 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - "Susan Gardner, Visions" (1973 April 28-May 19) (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - "The Articulate Surface: Drawings" (1973) (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - "Is Beauty the Making One of Opposites?", Part I (1973 September) (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - "Is Beauty the Making One of Opposites?", Part II (1973 October 13-November 9) (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - "Astrid Fitzgerald and Carol Rosen, Above, Below and On the Level" (1973 November 10-December 7) (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - "Big and Small, An Exhibition of Miniature Graphics, 1973/1974" (1973 December 8-1974 January 4) (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - "Conflict/Contrast/Composition" (1974 January 4- January 31) (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - "The Opposites on Greene Street" (1974 February 2-March 1), 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - "Chuck Magistro" (1974 March 9-April 5) (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - "Good and Evil: Aesthetic Opposites" (1974 April 6-May 3), 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - "The Opposites This Summer: Part I" (1975 June 21-July 31) (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - "The Opposites This Summer: Part II" (1975 August 2-September 11, 1975), 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - "Surface to Begin With, '75" (1975 September 20-October 16) (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - "Lee Adler, Paintings and Silkscreens" (1975 October 18-November 13) (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - "Understanding Shoes, An Exhibition of Works by Richard Karwoski" (1975 November 15-December 11), 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - "Big and Small, 1975/1976" (1975 December 16-1976 January 15) (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - "Intellect into Emotion" (1976 October 30-December 9), 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - "Thomas O'Donohue Etchings" (1976 February 3-February 28) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - "Art As Criticism" (1976 September 18-October 28), 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - "Chaim Koppelman Drawings" (1974 May 4-May 31), 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - "The Opposites This Summer" (1974 June 12-August 30) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - "Irwin Fleminger, Watercolors and Drawings" (1974 September 14-October 11), 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "The Gaiety of Art: Michael Cooper, Dennis Corrigan, and Richard Karwoski" (1974 October 19-November 22), 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - "Universe and Object" (1974 November 23-December 27) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - "20th Anniversary of the Terrain Gallery" (1975 February 8-March 20) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - "Intersection '75" (1975 March 29-April 24) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - "Andres Rodriquez Santos and Harry M. Zinzella" (1975 May 24-June 19) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - "Freedom and Order" (1976 March 2-April 13) (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - "Art All Along: A 22nd Anniversary Exhibition" (1977) (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - "Big and Small: Miniature Paintings, Prints, Drawings, and Photographs by 30 Contemporary Artists" (1976 December 14-1977 January 15), 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - "The Philosophy of Watercolor" (1976 April 27-May 29) (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - "The Arts, They're Here!" (1977 July 23-September 16), 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - "Black and White" (1977), 1972-1977 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - "Big and Small: Miniature Drawings, Paintings, Prints, and Photographs by 30 Contemporary Artists" (1977 December 16-1978 January 31), 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - "Self and Object" (1978 March 4-May 27) (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - "Color Surface Depth" (1978 November 11-December 13) (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - "Big and Small: Miniature Drawings, Paintings, Prints, and Photographs by 30 Artists, 1978/1979" (16 December 1978-1979 January 31) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - "Art As Kindness" (1979) (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - "The Honoring Eye, The Art of Drawing" (1979 June 2-August 31) (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - "The Opposites Make New York Beautiful" (1979 October 6-November 30) (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - "Big and Small: Miniature Drawings, Paintings, Prints, and Photographs by 50 Contemporary Artists" (1979 December 8-1980 January 31), 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - "The Opposites This Summer" (1980) (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - "25th Anniversary Exhibition: Is Beauty the Making One of Opposites?, 1955-1980" (1980) (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - "Is Beauty the Making One of Opposites?, Photography" (1980) (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - "The Print: A Oneness of Opposites" (1980 October 25-December 6) (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - "Big and Small: Miniature Drawings, Paintings, Prints, and Photographs, 1980/1981" (1980 December 13-January 31 1981) (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - "Big and Small: Miniature Drawings, Paintings, Prints, and Photographs by 50 Contemporary Artists, 1980/1981" (1980 December 5-1981), 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "Aesthetic Realists and Friends" (1981 February 28-April 11) (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - "Sameness and Difference: A Study" (1981), 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - "Imagination, Reality, and Aesthetics" (1981 September 26-October 31), 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Patricia Fennell, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - "Women Self Artist" (1982 January 30-March 9), 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - "Object/Universe" (1982 March 27-May 4) (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - "Drawing: Line, Shape, Meaning" (1982 May 15-June 19) (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - "The Opposites This Summer" (1982 July 10-September), 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - "Is Beauty the Making One of Opposites?" (1982) (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - "Big and Small: Miniature Drawings, Paintings, Prints, and Photographs, 1982/1983" (1982 December 12-January 1983) (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - "Earth, What It Has In It!" (1983 February 12-March 19), 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 41)